James Hanks

Designer / Developer

jameshanks.net

@jameshanks_

james.ra.hanks@gmail.com

+44 7557 914 933

PROFILE

I'm an experience designer and developer based in London. I strive to build elegant, user-centred and meaningful digital experiences that solve genuine problems. A recent graduate from Brunel University London with a First-Class degree in Digital Design, I am now a full-time Product Designer at Inktrap, a digital product studio based in Shoreditch, East London.

EXPERIENCE

Inktrap - Product Designer

LONDON • JULY 2019 - PRESENT

Hello Lamp Post - Digital Designer

LONDON • MARCH - AUGUST 2018

- Hello Lamp Post is public engagement platform, aiming to make smart cities more user-centred.
- Fully responsible for all design proposals, UI/UX design and front-end development.
- Promoted to sole designer, where I worked more closely with clients and senior team members.
- · Implemented a succinct agile design methodology; which the company is still currently using.
- Before returning to university, my design work helped the company join Facebook's London-based accelerator program.

PAN Studio - Design Intern

LONDON • AUGUST 2017 - AUGUST 2018

- Assisted the team on a wide variety of design projects throughout the year, from user experience design to animation.
- · Created an animatic and led audience feedback sessions before animating, editing and mixing the final video.
- Exceeded client expectations and the animation was published on their homepage and social channels, as opposed to solely being used internally. The client went on to commission a second video, based on the former's success.

Run An Empire - UI/UX Intern

LONDON • AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2018

- Run An Empire is a real-world mobile strategy running game.
- Implemented high-fidelity user interface assets and visual design within the product.
- Completed numerous quality assurance sessions and in-depth user communication in ZenDesk.
- Applied this research to better inform ideation stages and further user testing.

EDUCATION

Brunel University London

Digital Design BSc

Grade: First-Class Honours

2015 - 2019

City College Brighton & Hove

UAL Foundation Diploma in Art and Design: Graphic Design Grade: Distinction

2014 - 2015

INTERESTS

I am keen on fine art, creating sculptures and illustrations in my free time. I also enjoy running, which I do to support both my mental and physical health. Thank you for reading.

KEY SKILLS

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Node.js, MongoDB **Software:** Sketch, Figma, Adobe CC, InVision, Unity

Languages: Spanish (Conversational)

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS/ACTIVITIES

Brand Director

Brunel Digital

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JUNE 2019

Design Academy Participant

Design Council

JANUARY - MARCH 2017